"Hear us. Hear us."
“‘聽我們說…
"Hear our cries."
聽我們的聲音
"Our friend is trapped under a tree, unable to move."
我們的夥伴被倒下的 樹木壓住了，動彈不得’
"The animals looked into the girl's eyes and pleaded in their hearts."
動物們注視著 少女的眼睛並在內心說道
"Save him." "Please."
‘救救牠’、‘拜託’
"Then, the girl saved the squirrel trapped under the tree."
接著少女便拯救了 那隻被樹壓住的松鼠
"This girl has a special power."
因為少女擁有特殊的能力
"When she locks eyes with another,
那個能力就是在互相對望時
only then can she hear the voice in their heart."
她可以聽到對方的心聲”
Dolce &amp; Chocolat. is known for
說到朵契與巧克力
their cute and delicious chocolate and coffee,
就會聯想到好吃又可愛的 招牌商品巧克力與咖啡
but they both use cacao beans that were meant to be discarded--
而這兩項都是使用 原本要廢棄的可可豆…
We don't use cacao beans.
並不是用可可豆
These shells, known as cacao pods,
這個外殼稱為可可果莢
hold about 30 seeds surrounded by flesh, which we call the cacao pulp.
裡面大約會有30顆 被可可果肉包覆的種子
And this is a cacao bean.
而這就是可可豆
Okay.
這樣啊
Boss sure is aggressive today.
社長今天也好強勢喔
Chocolate usually only uses cacao nibs,
巧克力通常只會使用
which are cacao beans with their husks removed.
這個去除了可可豆殼的可可碎粒
But these discarded husks can still be used to make delicious chocolate.
但剩餘遭到廢棄的部分 明明也能做出美味的巧克力
Isn't that ridiculous?
你不覺得很奇怪嗎？
Y-Yes.
是的，沒錯
We use cacao husks that would usually be discarded
敝公司所販售的是 使用原本會被廢棄的可可豆殼
to produce chocolate, chocolate-flavored coffee, and other everyday goods.
製作而成的巧克力 可可風味咖啡與居家用品
I'm going out to the shop.
我去店鋪喔
-See you. -Okay.
-慢走 -好
Chocolate and coffee made from discarded cacao.
使用廢棄可可製作的巧克力與咖啡
That's my life right now.
那就是我現在人生的一切
That looks so tasty. I want some too.
看起來好好吃，我也想吃
No, Noa.
不行喔
But you always say no.
為什麼每次都說不行？
We're not here for you today, Noa.
今天不是為了你才來的啊
Why? I want some.
為什麼？但人家想吃啦
-I wanna eat some. -Noa, calm down.
-我想吃啦！ -乃愛，乖一點啦…
Can we help you, Sir?
客人，請問怎麼了嗎？
I'm sorry.
不好意思
We're here to buy a gift,
我們是來買伴手禮的
but she insists on having some too.
但這孩子說她也想吃
Mind your manners.
別任性了
I want some too.
我也想吃
I don't have enough money to buy two.
身上帶的錢不夠買兩個
And Noa gets cavities so easily.
而且乃愛又容易蛀牙
Can I have one box of ten?
我要買這一盒十顆裝的
Um…
那個…
I also recommend this.
我也推薦這項商品
It's the same price as that one, but…
價格跟那項相同，不過…
Then I can bring one as a gift
選這款就能一瓶當伴手禮
and take the other home.
另一瓶在家吃
And this one uses xylitol instead of sugar,
順帶一提，這款巧克力 是使用木糖醇來代替砂糖
so cavities aren't a concern.
所以吃了也不容易蛀牙
Really?
真的嗎？
She always gets cavities.
這孩子很容易蛀牙
Really? This is perfect.
是嗎？真是剛好呢
Hey, how does this chocolate sound?
乃愛，買這款巧克力好嗎？
Really? I love you, Dad!
可以買嗎？最喜歡你了，爸爸！
I love you too!
爸爸也愛你喔！
Brush your teeth after, okay?
那吃了之後你會乖乖刷牙嗎？
Okay.
我會的
Wow, this is incredible.
哇，天啊
Isn't this pretty, Dad?
好漂亮喔，爸爸
I'm glad you like it.
太好了
I always wanted to bring you here, Yuri.
我一直想帶你來這裡，侑里
Oh, what?
啊，什麼？
KIRITAPPU CAPE
（霧多布岬）
Dad, sea otters!
爸爸，是海獺耶！
They're really here!
原來真的有海獺啊！
Oh, I see them.
喔，看到了…
Since we're here, let's take a closer look tomorrow.
難得都來了，明天靠近一點看看吧
Yeah, I'd love that.
好啊，我想去
Yuri!
侑里！
Ever since that accident,
自從發生那場意外後
I've been able to hear the thoughts of anyone I locked eyes with.
我就變得能夠聽到 與我目光交會的人的心聲
It was confusing at first, and my feelings were often hurt.
起初我不知所措，也為此受了很多傷
But I realized that it isn't all bad once you figure out
但我發現只要明白適當的共處方式
how to properly use this power.
就不全然是壞事
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
-謝謝 -不客氣
People's thoughts aren't always out of ill will.
因為人心並非只有惡意
-Get home safely. -Bye-bye.
-路上小心 -再見
You're so good at this, Yuri.
侑里小姐真的好厲害喔
It's almost scary how well you can read people's feelings.
對於人心的洞察力有時敏銳到嚇人呢
You think?
是嗎？
But why can't you get a boyfriend?
為什麼這樣還交不到男朋友？
Is it because you're still caught up on an ex from high school?
該不會是還放不下 高中時期的前男友？
People's thoughts?
內心的想法？
Yeah.
對
It's not like that.
並不是那樣啦
But I just know…
我只是明白…
how hard it can be to find romance when you have this power.
要帶著這樣的能力 談戀愛是多麼地困難
When people fall in love,
因為人一旦墜入愛河
they end up wishing…
儘管知道會受傷
To know their partner's thoughts,
也會忍不住想要去了解
even if it may hurt them.
對方的心
I'm so hungry.
肚子餓了
GOHAN RECEIVE ORDER
（送飯 承接訂單）
12 MINUTES, 360 YEN
（12分鐘，360圓）
Time for food.
來吃飯…
"This is a secret, but if you want pibimbap,
“這是祕密喔，韓式‘扳’飯的話
there's a restaurant called Ondol Eatery that tastes better."
有一間名叫暖坑食堂的店更好吃”
A sea otter?
海獺？
Aihara.
相原
Yes?
是
You switched the coffee bean order numbers.
咖啡豆的訂貨量寫反了
How did you mix up Colombian and Jamaican beans?
為什麼會把哥倫比亞和牙買加搞錯？
I don't think I'm suited for tedious jobs like this.
我可能不適合做這種雜務
Something with more responsibility or meaning…
那種責任更重或是有成就感的工作
-That might-- -You can only go up one step at a time.
-應該比較… -樓梯必須一階一階爬
-What? -Whatever job you get,
-什麼？ -做任何事
do it with positivity and grace.
都別灰心喪志，態度要積極
-Makes sense. -Yeah.
-有道理耶 -是啊
For starters…
總之…
Is Hanaoka interested in anything other than work?
花岡他有對什麼 工作以外的事物感興趣嗎？
-Who knows? -It's so strange.
-誰知道 -真是神祕
I wonder if he has any hobbies.
他都沒有嗜好嗎？
Can't you just talk to him about work?
和他聊工作不就好了嗎？
Then the conversation won't go anywhere. Anyway--
那樣咱沒辦法延展話題哪，對了…
Sorry, Kame.
龜哥，抱歉
-I'm clocking out. -What?
-我要下班了 -什麼？
Jeez.
天啊
Why is this here?
為何要放在這種地方啦？
Seriously?
真是的
It's okay. I'll handle this.
沒關係，我來處理
-Thanks. -It's fine. I'm climbing the ladder now.
-謝謝 -不客氣，因為我正在爬樓梯
I've been thinking,
我從之前就在想
aren't these better on the wall instead of the desk?
這種東西與其放著 不如掛在牆上比較好對吧？
Then, they'd be out of the way.
那樣就不會撞到，也方便打掃
We should've bought those in the first place.
我們是不是一開始就該買那種的？
You can go to lunch after your meeting.
會議結束後你可以去吃午餐
Thank you.
謝謝，我拿去吃了
-That's-- -No, Aihara.
-那裡是… -別過去，相原
Interrupting Boss's meal will get you killed.
打擾社長吃東西是會被抹殺的喔
Kill--
抹…
Thanks, Hanaoka. What is this?
花岡，謝謝你，這是什麼商品？
Convenience store by the station, vanilla cream flavor, 124 yen.
在車站前的便利商店買的 香草奶油口味，124圓
Impressive. Thanks, as always.
不愧是你，謝謝你總是如此貼心
And if we change all the trash cans to the ones that hang on the walls,
另外，垃圾桶若要全部改成壁掛式
it'll cost us 44,450 yen in expenses.
需要花費44450圓的經費
For now, I'll have everyone put theirs under their desk.
我會暫時規定 大家將垃圾桶放在桌子底下
Impressive. Sorry, as always.
真佩服你，不好意思總是麻煩你
-You'll miss your meeting. -Oh!
-開會要遲到了喔 -啊！
I'm so hungry.
肚子好餓
I'm so hungry!
肚子好餓！
"Pibimbap."
“韓式‘扳’飯”
They meant bibimbap, right?
是在說“韓式拌飯”吧？
Ondol Eatery.
暖坑食堂
SIGNATURE DISH, BIBIMBAP
（特製韓式拌飯）
Hm?
嗯？
A-OK
（萬事如意）
270 YEN ONDOL EATERY
（270圓 暖坑食堂）
Let's go.
出發囉
Enjoy.
請享用
Thank you for the food.
我開動了
Is this made of bagasse?
是甘蔗渣材質嗎？
It’s microwave-safe but not oven-safe, right?
是不是可微波，但不能放烤箱？
"Hope this energizes you."
“請補給能量
"This restaurant's Korean pancakes are good too."
這間店的韓式煎餅也很好吃”
Korean pancakes.
韓式煎餅
Seafood. Kimchi. Potato.
海鮮、泡菜、馬鈴薯
Let's get some.
吃一些吧
BEST BIBIMBAP EVER. I FEEL ENERGIZED. THANK YOU.
（這是我吃過最好吃的韓式拌飯 成功補給了能量，謝謝你）
I FEEL ENERGIZED.
成功補給了能量）
Cute.
好可愛
Enjoy.
請享用
"The rapokki is to die for."
“辣炒年糕泡麵也是極品佳餚”
Rapokki?
辣炒年糕泡麵？
That looks delicious.
看起來好美味
I want some, but…
雖然我是很想吃啦…
RAPOKKI
（辣炒年糕泡麵）
When you visit home, you have to buy souvenirs, right?
回老家不是都會買伴手禮嗎？
You gotta think about who to buy them for, right?
然後就會開始思考要買給誰
But the first person I thought of wasn't my boyfriend.
我當時第一個想到的不是男友
It was my co-workers.
而是同事們
My mom asked me if I wasn't getting him anything,
我媽問我“不用買給男友嗎？”
and that's when I remembered him.
我才終於想起他
I realized, "This is bad."
於是我驚覺這實在不太妙
Are you listening?
你有在聽嗎？
Sorry, so basically, what are you trying to say?
抱歉，所以你想講的是什麼？
So, basically,
我想說的是
I think it's true love when you want to buy them souvenirs.
我覺得有沒有愛 從是否會想買伴手禮就看得出來
Well, I don't have a guy to buy souvenirs for,
是喔，因為我沒有想送伴手禮的對象
nor would I buy a souvenir as an excuse to see one.
也沒有想藉送禮的名義跟誰見面
So I don't really get it.
所以可能不太懂
I guess you can't relate.
對你來說太難理解了啊
Yeah… What?
對，什麼？
I've never had this before. It's delicious.
話說我第一次吃這個，但好好吃
Isn't it? I got a great source of information.
對吧？不愧是可靠的情報來源
Did someone suggest this place?
有人推薦給你的？
A food delivery guy. He always leaves me notes.
一位外送員，他每次都會留紙條
-What? -Yeah?
-什麼？ -怎麼了？
Isn't that shady?
那樣不是很可疑嗎？
What? Why?
怎麼會？為何這麼說？
That person guides me to delicious food.
他會引領我找到美食
He's like a god.
是如同神一般的人
Don't look at me like that.
別用那種眼神看我
Maybe you feel a spark then.
所以他讓你心動了啊
YOUR ORDER HAS BEEN CANCELED
（您的訂單已取消）
Why?
為什麼？
Why, God?
為什麼？神啊
70-MINUTE WAIT 60-MINUTE WAIT
（等候70分鐘 等候60分鐘）
Why's there such a long wait?
為什麼這麼花時間啦？
Is it some kind of holiday today?
今天是什麼節日嗎？
It's raining.
下雨了
That's why it's taking so long.
原來是因為在下雨所以才很花時間
I'm so hungry. Oh no, I'm so hungry.
好餓啊，不妙，超級餓的
Huh?
什麼？
What?
這是怎樣？
Oh, I'm sorry.
啊，對不起
Sorry! I'm really sorry!
對不起！非常抱歉！
Are you God?
你就是神？
God?
神？
No, I mean, the delivery guy?
不，沒事，你是外送員？
Oh, were you my customer?
啊，你就是客人嗎？
Um, are you mad?
請問你在生氣嗎？
No, I'm not.
我沒有在生氣
My bike slid a lot in the rain
我因為下雨，腳踏車滑了一下
and ruined the food.
訂的餐被影響到，無法拿給客人吃
I wrote this to say I'm sorry.
我想道歉，所以寫了紙條
Was the food completely ruined?
餐點是完全不能吃的狀態嗎？
If the container was just smashed a bit…
如果只是容器稍微撞到…
It went tumbling down.
它滾下去了
It rolled and rolled down the hill.
沿著斜坡滾…
I understand.
我明白了
Bye, then.
再見
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
To buy food.
我要去買飯
It's dangerous in this heavy rain.
雨很大，很危險耶
It's windy too.
風也很強
But I need to eat.
但我需要吃飯
I'm truly sorry.
真的非常抱歉
I'm just hungry.
我只是餓了
I'm incredibly hungry.
我真的很餓
I'm starving!
肚子餓得不得了！
-Are you mad? -I'm not mad.
-你在生氣嗎？ -我沒有在生氣
Do you by chance like soondubu?
那個，你喜歡豆腐鍋嗎？
Soondubu?
豆腐鍋？
Very much.
非常喜歡
Got it. Please wait here.
好，請等我一下
Five minutes.
五分鐘
Please wait in your room!
請回家等我！
I SLIPPED ON MY BIKE AND DROPPED YOUR FOOD. I'M VERY SORRY.
（下雨天腳踏車滑了一下 不小心弄掉餐點，非常抱歉）
Oh, here's your soondubu.
啊，這是豆腐鍋
I made some earlier.
我剛好有煮一些
Have some.
請享用吧
-What? -Um…
-什麼？ -那個…
I live in Tatsumi Building by the greenway.
我就住在綠道上的多津美大樓
It's nearby.
很近
What?
什麼？
Oh, could it be you don't trust the food?
啊，你覺得很可疑嗎？
Of course, you wouldn't. Don't worry.
我想也是，不過別擔心
There's nothing weird in it.
裡面沒有加奇怪的東西
I'm Yun Tae-o.
我是尹泰晤
I'm 26 years old, and came to Japan almost two years ago.
來到日本快滿兩年，26歲
I'm from Korea.
我來自韓國
I'm not anyone suspicious.
絕對不是什麼可疑人士
It's delicious.
這很好吃
It'll energize you.
給你能量補給
Here.
請享用
Well then, I'm truly sorry.
那我走了，真的非常抱歉
A sea otter?
海獺？
God's soondubu.
神的豆腐鍋
It's warm.
好溫暖
It's rare to see you without an appetite.
你竟然不吃飯，真是稀奇
You need your strength.
這樣會沒精神喔
I can't drink coffee. It's too bitter.
我不敢喝咖啡，好苦
This coffee
這杯咖啡裡面啊
uses cacao, just like chocolate.
跟巧克力一樣含有可可喔
It's just like chocolate?
跟巧克力一樣？
Even though it's not sweet?
但明明不甜
Yeah.
是啊
It can be sweet or bitter depending on how you use it.
它會根據使用方式變苦或變甜
Life's the same way.
人生也一樣
It all depends on you whether it's bitter or sweet.
你可以自己決定 要讓人生變苦或變甜喔
I don't get it.
我不懂啦
It's so bitter.
好苦啊
It's so sweet.
好甜
Now, eat your omurice too.
那你把蛋包飯也吃了吧
Thank you for the food.
我開動了
I'm home, Mom.
媽，我回來了
I'm famished.
肚子餓了
Oh, I gave away my soondubu.
對了，我把豆腐鍋送人了
I'm starving!
肚子餓得不得了！
That face
那個表情
was terrifying.
真是嚇人啊
In other words,
也就是說
when God talks, it's in Japanese.
神說話的時候是講日語…
Are you mad?
你在生氣嗎？
But his thoughts are in Korean.
但他在心裡是講韓語
It's bitter.
好苦啊
Oh, sorry.
啊，抱歉
Go ahead.
請過
Thank you!
謝謝！
Professor Zaitsu, good morning!
財津教授！早安！
Oh, good morning, Tae-o!
喔，泰晤，早安！
RESEARCH LAB WILDLIFE CONSERVATION MAJOR
（研究室，獸醫科學研究科 野生生物保育學專攻）
Did you sleep well, fishes one through six?
有睡飽嗎？小魚們 一、二、三、四、五、六
Good morning!
早安！
Morning.
早安
Good morning, Tae-o. Humidity went down 2%.
早安，泰晤，濕度下降了2%
Sorry.
抱歉
Did you eat, Senpai?
學長，你吃飯了嗎？
Yeah, hey.
吃了，辛苦了
BEST BIBIMBAP EVER. I FEEL ENERGIZED. THANK YOU.
（這是我吃過最好吃的韓式拌飯 成功補給了能量，謝謝你）
What is that?
那是什麼？
Someone replied to me.
有人回覆我了
Oh, at your delivery job?
啊，你是說外送打工嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
It's the first reply I've ever gotten.
這是我第一次收到回覆
I was really happy.
我好開心
What a nice person.
對方人真好
Yes--
對…
I'm starving!
肚子餓得不得了！
Is she a nice person?
她人好嗎？
Bravo.
好極了
"Good food is the best way to energize." Your mom would always say that, right?
“美食是最棒的能量補給” 你母親時常這樣說吧？
Yes.
是的
That reminds me,
說到這個
Park sent us some kimchi.
朴寄泡菜來了喔
This year's kimchi tastes like your mother's cooking too.
今年也完美重現了你母親的味道
Yes, this is great!
好耶，太棒了！
I want some too.
我也想吃
We only got enough for me and Tae-o.
對方只有寄泰晤跟我的份
Professor, can't you go with the flow?
教授，你難道沒聽過 “臨機應變”這個詞嗎？
Because of you, this is the only kimchi I can eat.
說實在的，拜這泡菜所賜 現在我挑剔到非這個就不吃
Do I count as a sea otter foodie, spending five million yen a year on food?
我是否為一年花五百萬圓伙食費的 海獺美食家的夥伴呢？
Are you a sea otter?
你是海獺嗎？
Kyoshuku desuga.
恐怕是的
You don't resemble one. You look totally different.
不像，外觀完全不同
Kyoshuku desu.
真是過意不去
"Kyoshuku…"?
“過意不去”？
What's "kyoshuku"?
什麼是“過意不去”？
Oh, it means sorry or thank you.
這個嘛，就是“對不起” 或是“謝謝”的意思
He's sorry?
他感到抱歉？
Which is it?
他說的是哪個意思？
The samples arrived for our Valentine's Day product!
情人節限定商品的樣品寄來囉！
-Whoa! -They're here!
-哇！ -寄來了！
-Here, Boss. -Oh, thanks.
-來，社長 -啊，謝謝
-Here, Nishina. -Thanks.
-來，仁科小姐 -謝謝
Red was a good choice for the packaging. It pops.
包裝選紅色是對的呢，好華麗
The taste's just as good.
味道也沒輸喔
The strong bitter taste of the vanilla with 72% cacao gave me goosebumps.
苦味強的香草配上 72%可可時我都打哆嗦了
-It's Mahiro's masterpiece. -Yes.
-這是你的自信之作嘛 -沒錯
This is so good. Anyone would be happy to receive this.
超好吃的，收到這個絕對會很開心
Right?
對吧？
It'll energize you.
給你能量補給
Here.
請享用
You won't see her for another six months.
下次見面是半年後對吧？
Why won't you see your daughter for six months?
明明是你女兒 為什麼半年後才能見面？
May I speak to you, Mahiro?
真尋小姐，方便佔用一點時間嗎？
I'd like to ask you something later.
我稍後有事想請教你
What?
怎麼了？
I think you should go bold and choose this one.
這種時候應該要毅然決然地選這個
But this would normally be better.
但通常選這個比較正常吧
Wouldn't you prefer something rare and precious?
要彰顯限定商品的稀有價值吧？
I feel like our flagship product's timeless charm is a great selling point.
招牌商品的普世價值 應該也足夠有魅力了
Is there some kind of trouble?
遇到麻煩了嗎？是什麼事？
A thank you gift for the soondubu.
是關於豆腐鍋的回禮
What?
什麼東西？
A gift to God.
要給神的供品
A thank you for his hospitality.
要還一頓飯的恩情
If this isn't about work, then go home.
我說啊，不是在討論公事就回家去
Which would you be happier to get?
你收到哪個會比較開心？
You're costing us electricity, so go home.
在你們閒聊的期間 也是會算電費的，快回家
Wait.
等一下
Wouldn't giving chocolate at this time of the year mean something special?
說起來送巧克力這個行為本身 在此時期會不會有特別的含意？
VALENTINE'S DAY IN KOREA
（韓國情人節）
AS IN JAPAN, WOMEN GIVE CHOCOLATES TO THOSE THEY LIKE
（韓國跟日本一樣 女性也會送巧克力給心儀對象）
Go home right now.
現在就回家吧
Why Korea?
為什麼是韓國？
Just because.
沒什麼特別原因
-What?
-什麼？
I live in Tatsumi Building by the greenway.
我就住在綠道上的多津美大樓
TATSUMI BUILDING
（多津美大樓）
Excuse me.
打擾了
YUN
（尹）
Yun.
“尹”
-I'm sorry. -What?
-不好意思… -什麼？
Did I accidentally do something again?
我又做了什麼嗎？
Oh, not at all.
啊，不是的
I came to return the soup jar.
我來還湯罐
I see.
這樣啊
Kyoshuku desu.
真是過意不去
That's what I should be saying.
那是我該說的
It was incredibly delicious.
非常好吃
Really?
真的嗎？
It was delicious and warm.
美味又溫暖
It really energized me, truly.
真的讓我打起了精神
Thank you for the food.
謝謝你的招待
Who are you?
你是誰？
Oh, you gave me the soondubu the other day.
啊，我是前幾天收下豆腐鍋的人
I know that.
我知道
You seem like a different person from before,
因為你跟之前彷彿是不同人
so I was a bit surprised.
所以我有點驚訝
Oh, really?
是嗎？
Oh, this soap is…
啊，這個香皂…
It's not much, but I wanted to thank you.
雖然只是一點心意，這是回禮
-Well, then… -Um, wait one second.
-那我走了… -那個，請稍等一下
Let's see. Where did I put it again?
我看看，放到哪去了？
I use this soap too.
我也有在用這款香皂
Yesterday, I used this to blow bubbles.
昨天我也有用它來吹泡泡
Wait one second.
等一下喔
Um, where did I put that again?
我找找，那個放到哪去了？
Eco-friendly soap bubbles.
環境友善的泡泡
-Come with me. -What?!
-跟我來 -什麼？
Watch this.
看好囉
This is…
這是…
He's a god after all.
他果然是神
-What? -No, it's nothing.
-什麼？ -不，沒事
These bubbles are eco-friendly, so rest assured.
這款香皂對地球很友善，請放心
And they don't harm humans either.
而且對人類也很友善呢
You can use it as much as you want
不必擔心環境
without worrying about the environment.
可以盡情且隨意地使用
Wouldn't it be nice if more and more things were made like that?
真希望那樣的東西 能越來越多，對吧？
It would be very, very nice.
如果越來越多就好了
I'm having japchae today.
今天是雜菜冬粉
Is that okay with you?
可以嗎？
What?
什麼？
-Actually, I think I'll go-- -It's done.
-那個，我還是回去… -煮好了
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -什麼事？
Are you mad--
請問你在生氣…
I'm not mad!
我沒有在生氣！
Let's eat.
我們開動吧
But…
不過…
Oh no, I can't understand him at all.
不行，完全不懂
Oh, it's okay.
啊，不用擔心
There's nothing weird in it.
裡面沒有奇怪的東西
Don't be mad.
請你別生氣
Please eat.
請吃吧
Thank you for the food.
我開動了
It's delicious!
好好吃！
Get energized.
能量補給
Why are you smiling so much?
你為什麼要一直笑？
I'm happy.
因為我很開心
It's been a while
我好久沒有
since I ate with someone at home.
跟別人在家裡吃飯了
Time to eat.
我開動了
I'm eating.
我已經開動了
That was a great meal.
謝謝招待
It was absolutely delicious.
真的非常好吃
Oh, now I get it.
我懂了，原來是這樣啊
You get mad when you're hungry.
你肚子餓了就會生氣是吧？
Are you talking about me?
你說我嗎？
Did that help you
能量補給
get energized?
成功了嗎？
Yes, I'm fully charged.
是的，現在能量滿滿
Cute.
真可愛
Kimchi…
泡菜…
I said, "Do you like it?"
“喜歡嗎？”是這個意思
Yes, I like kimchi.
對，我喜歡泡菜
If there's super spicy kimchi
非常辣的
and slightly spicy kimchi,
和只有一點辣的
which do you prefer?
你比較喜歡哪種？
The super spicy kimchi
非常辣的
might be hard for me to eat.
我可能有點不敢吃
Got it.
我明白了
BEST BIBIMBAP EVER
（這是我吃過最好吃的韓式拌飯）
Why did you keep this?
你為什麼還留著？
It's so poorly drawn.
我畫得這麼醜
The sea otter?
你說海獺嗎？
You were the first to reply to me.
這是第一次有人回覆我
I was happy.
我很高興
So,
所以說啊
I like this sea otter.
我很喜歡這隻海獺
It seems you like sea otters.
看來你很愛海獺呢
I love them.
超愛的
I'm studying sea otters at graduate school.
我目前正在研究所研究海獺
Are you studying endangered animals?
是瀕危物種的研究嗎？
Yes.
沒錯
Did you know that sea otters are endangered?
你知道海獺是瀕危物種嗎？
On the 2020 Red List,
2020年在紅皮書名錄中
sea otters were listed an A1 endangered animal.
海獺被指定為瀕危1A類
A1 endangered animals
所謂的瀕危1A類指的是
are at extremely high risk of going extinct in the wild
“在不遠的將來於野外滅絕之危險性
in the near future.
極高的物種”
Why do you like sea otters?
為什麼你喜歡海獺？
Why?
你問理由？
No reason.
沒有原因
Kids are cute.
小孩很可愛
Ghosts are scary.
鬼很可怕
It's the same idea.
就是那種感覺
I like them because I like them.
因為覺得喜歡所以喜歡
Simple as that, right?
不都是這樣嗎？
Do you like sea otters?
你喜歡海獺嗎？
-Yes. -Really?!
-喜歡 -真的嗎？
We're the same, huh?
我們一樣呢
Wow, you like them too?
是喔，原來你也喜歡？
I mean,
畢竟啊
sea otters are so cute.
海獺很可愛嘛
You're so innocent.
你真是天真無邪
"Innocent"?
“天真無邪”？
Like a child.
就是純真可愛
True to your feelings.
個性直率
That's what it means.
就是這意思
When I think about it, when I was doing my part-time job today,
說到這個，我今天打工的時候
I was called carefree.
被說看起來很“無憂無慮”
Does that mean the same thing?
那是相同的意思嗎？
Well…
這個嘛…
You have a positive attitude.
是指樂觀
That's what it means.
那類的意思
I have a positive attitude and I'm true to myself.
我既樂觀又直率
I agree.
是啊
How old are you?
你幾歲？
Me?
我？
Yes, you.
沒錯，就是你
-Thirty. -And your name?
-30歲 -名字呢？
I'm Motomiya.
本宮
I mean your first name.
我想問下面的名字
I'm Yuri.
我是侑里
Yuri.
侑里
Yuri, huh?
侑里小姐，是吧？
That's a cute name.
真是可愛的名字
POLLOCK ROE PASTA
（明太子義大利麵）
LEAVE AT DOOR
（放在門口）
RECEIVE IN PERSON
（當面取餐）
Today's delivery is pasta.
今天送來了義大利麵
Thank you.
謝謝
Enjoy.
請享用
-Yuri, today's-- -Thank you.
-侑里小姐，今天… -謝謝
She must be hungry today.
今天她肚子很餓啊
Cute.
真可愛
Are you a mad Yuri today?
今天是生氣的侑里小姐？
Or a nice Yuri?
還是溫柔的侑里小姐？
-What? -Hm?
-什麼？ -嗯？
NAMASTE NAAN CURRY
（那摩斯戴烤餅咖哩）
GET ENERGIZED!
（能量補給！）
"Get energized."
“能量補給”
Thanks for the food.
我開動了
Yeah, this is good.
真棒，好好吃
Where'd you buy this?
這是哪家的便當？
At the food truck in the back.
我在後方的餐車買的
The university president told me it's good.
校長跟我說很好吃
Even the president's looking out for you?
連那種大人物都對你疼愛有加？
You're like a penguin.
你簡直就是企鵝嘛
An emperor penguin perhaps?
那應該是皇帝企鵝吧？
You're affectionate and true to yourself when you express your feelings.
容易親近，會用全身表現 喜怒哀樂的直率性格也一模一樣
Hm? True to myself?
嗯？直率？
Oh, "innocent," right?
我知道，就是“天真無邪”對吧？
I'm innocent and carefree.
我既天真無邪又無憂無慮
Tae-o, that's not something to be proud of.
泰晤，那種話不該講得那麼得意
It's an insult.
那算是壞話
Is it an insult?
是壞話嗎？
Carefree means you don't think about anything.
因為說人“無憂無慮” 是在諷刺一個人什麼都沒在想
You have a positive attitude.
是指樂觀
That's what it means.
那類的意思
She really is a wonderful person.
她果然是很棒的人
A wonderful person? Is this love?
很棒的人？泰晤，你戀愛了嗎？
It's not love.
不是戀愛
Not yet.
還不是
Not yet?
還不是？
I'll let you know if it turns into love.
要是發展成戀愛，我會告訴你
Bravo.
好極了
-Tae-o, you start tomorrow, right? -Yes.
-泰晤，那件事是從明天開始對吧？ -是的
I'm nervous, as if I'm the one going.
我緊張到像是自己的事
However, as Tae-o's foster parent,
但身為泰晤的代養者
I must be like the golden eagle, starving its child so they leave the nest.
我也必須向金鵰父母學習 讓雛鳥餓肚子，催促孩子離巢
This is bad.
這可不行
My nerves raised my body temperature, making the room warmer.
緊張引發高體溫，導致溫度上升了
Thanks, that was delicious.
很好吃，謝謝
Hey, do I…
我問你喔
What?
什麼事？
Do I have a habit of getting angry
我有肚子餓了
-when I'm hungry? -Yes.
-就會生氣的習慣嗎？ -有
I do? Since when?
有嗎？什麼時候開始的？
Before I even met you.
從我初次遇見你時就是那樣
So, since I was in university?
所以是從大學時期開始的？
Why didn't you tell me?
為何沒跟我說？
You never asked.
你又沒問
I see.
這樣啊
You're always like that, Hanaoka.
的確符合你的個性
Motomiya, you're so oblivious when it comes to yourself.
你只要談到自己的事 就會瞬間變得一無所知耶
What?
什麼？
Yet you can read others so easily.
觀察別人時明明就敏銳得要命
You think so?
是嗎？
I'm saying
我要說的是
that it really helps our company out.
你那點對我們公司很有幫助
You can sense how others feel
你每次都能察覺別人的心情
and always make a calm decision that matches that.
並配合他人的心思下冷靜的判斷
That's a great advantage for entrepreneurs.
身為公司經營者，那是一個強項
Thanks.
謝謝
-I'm back. -Welcome back.
-我回來了 -回來啦
The purchase order for our limited edition Valentine's Day goods
我記得情人節限定商品的訂貨單
should be sent by next week, right?
是下週之前寄出就可以吧？
Oh right, Aihara.
對了，相原
Send the purchase order for Valentine's Day goods today, okay?
情人節限定商品的訂貨單 記得在今天之內寄出去喔
What?
什麼？
Oh, sure.
啊，好的
That was today? That was a close call.
原來是今天？好險啊
Hello?
喂？
HARMONY CARE CENTER
（和諧照護中心）
I use this power to protect my company.
我使用這個能力來守護公司
It's for the sake of my dream.
那是為了我的夢想
For my employees.
也是為了員工
But most of all…
但最主要的…
Come in.
請進
Ms. Motomiya.
本宮小姐
Dad.
爸爸
He got phlegm in his throat and had trouble breathing.
他稍微卡了一點痰，導致呼吸不順
Is he okay?
狀況還好嗎？
We sucked it out, so he's fine now.
已經吸過痰了，所以沒有問題
Thank goodness.
太好了
Your daughter came to visit.
你女兒來了喔
Isn't that great?
真是太好了
I'll excuse myself then.
那我離開了
-Thank you. -Of course.
-謝謝 -不客氣
Dad, are you okay? Does it hurt?
爸爸，你還好嗎？難不難受？
I'm fine.
我沒事…
They're making a big fuss over nothing.
只是出點狀況就搞得那麼誇張
I need them to worry at least that much.
他們要是沒關心到這種程度 我就傷腦筋了
I guess that's true.
說得也是
Oh, give me the usual smell.
對了，讓我聞聞平時那個香氣吧
Right.
對喔
Here you go.
來
Yes, what a nice aroma.
真棒啊，好香
That's right.
對了
We made this year's Valentine's Day product.
今年的情人節商品完成了喔
Oh, show me.
是喔，讓我看看…
Sure.
好
On that day 12 years ago…
12年前的那天…
Ta-da!
你看！
At the same time my father lost mobility,
在我父親的身體變得無法活動的同時
I gained the ability to hear people's thoughts.
我開始變得能夠聽到別人的心聲
Hey!
喂！
Yuri!
侑里！
-Someone! -Hey, come back!
-來人啊！ -喂，回來！
Yuri!
侑里！
It's okay. Dad's here to protect you.
沒事的，爸爸會保護你
Unfortunately,
很遺憾
I believe your father will never move again.
你父親的身體恐怕再也不能動了
In your father's case, the left and right side of his brain
以他的情況來說，由於左腦與右腦
have suffered a stroke,
皆有發生腦梗塞
making it difficult for him to communicate his thoughts.
他往後也會很難與人溝通
Dad.
爸爸
I'm sorry.
對不起
No, Yuri.
不對
It's not your fault.
這不是你的錯
Dad?
爸爸？
I'm glad you're safe, Yuri.
幸好你平安無事
I can hear you.
我聽得到
I can hear you…
我聽得到…
I can hear your voice, Dad.
我能聽到爸爸的聲音
Dad.
爸爸
Here is this month's bill.
這是本月份的
It includes today's medical expenses.
裡面也包含了今天的治療費
Okay.
好的
To continue sharing a life with my father,
今後為了和爸爸一起生活下去
I need money.
我需要錢
-Thank you.
-謝謝
That's why I decided to use this power to protect my company.
因此我下定決心 要用這個能力來守護公司
Because it's up to me whether to make life bitter or sweet.
因為要讓生活變苦或變甜 全都取決於我自己
-Ms. Motomiya. -Ms. Oki.
-本宮小姐 -大木小姐
-Thank you for earlier. -It's nothing.
-剛才謝謝你 -別客氣…
Makoto is so blessed to have a daughter who cares for him.
有這麼孝順的女兒，誠先生很幸福呢
She pays so much every month, even though there's no cure.
每個月付那麼多錢 明明也沒有方法治療
I feel so sorry for her.
真的好可憐
They can't even chat when she visits--
來探病甚至也不能對話…
Ms. Motomiya?
本宮小姐？
Oh, right.
啊
Please continue to take good care of my father.
今後也麻煩你照顧我父親了
Please come visit anytime.
我才要請你多多關照
-Get home safely. -Thank you.
-那麼路上小心 -好的
And yet…
即使如此
There are times when the bitterness is inevitable.
難免還是會有極為苦澀的時刻
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
You, the cute lady over there looking around everywhere!
就是那邊的你 正在東張西望的可愛女生！
Yuri, wait one second!
侑里小姐，請稍等一下！
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Yuri, this is great.
侑里小姐，太好了
Today's my last day with my part-time job,
今天是我最後一天打工
so I wanted to see you.
所以很想見你一面
I'm happy I got to see you.
能見到你，我很開心
If you'd like, let's do it together.
那個，你願意陪我嗎？
What?
什麼？
Huh?
什麼東西？
Remember how the wind and rain was really strong the other day?
前陣子有一天風雨不是很強嗎？
Oh, the day when your bike slipped and you couldn't deliver my food?
啊，你騎腳踏車滑了一下 餐點沒送達的那天？
Because of that, a lot of leaves flew over,
因為那天的關係，飛來很多樹葉
so I'm cleaning up.
所以我要打掃
Why are you doing that, Mr. Yun?
為什麼是尹先生打掃？
Call me Tae-o.
叫我泰晤
Why are you doing that, Tae-o?
為什麼是泰晤先生要打掃？
My landlord's back hurts.
因為房東腰痛
I'll show you how to do it first.
我先示範給你看
Here.
請看
Whoa.
哦
Now, then.
那麼…
This sucks them up.
按這邊是吸進去
This blows a lot of wind.
按這邊則是會轟地吹出風
Don't mix them up.
所以不能搞錯
Okay.
好
You're doing great.
做得很好
There are so many different leaves.
地上有好多種樹葉喔
-Whoa. -What?
-哇 -怎麼了？
This is a ginkgo leaf.
這是銀杏葉
Wild ginkgos are endangered.
野生的銀杏是瀕危物種
What? Is that true?
什麼？真的嗎？
This is a dawn redwood leaf.
這個水杉葉也是
-Really? -Yes.
-是嗎？ -對
Then…
那該不會…
-Is this one too? -That's…
-連這個也是？ -那種葉子…
a common one.
有很多喔
I'm glad.
太好了
What?
什麼？
What's the matter?
你怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒事
Don't look at me.
請不要看我
What?
什麼？
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
Have you gone crazy?
腦袋出問題了嗎？
Don't look.
不要看我
Don't look at my eyes.
不要看我的眼睛
Um…
那個…
Wow, this is pretty.
哇，好漂亮
So pretty.
很美喔
What?
什麼？
Oh, you're right.
啊，真的耶
These are the leaves we were cleaning up.
剛才本來還在打掃這些葉子
But now…
不過現在啊
they've become so pretty.
全都變成美麗的葉子了
Rather than bitter, make it sweet…
使其變甜，而非變苦
Thank you very much.
真的很感謝你
You've given me energy again.
你又讓我打起精神了
Yuri, you…
侑里小姐，你…
are like a different person every time we meet.
每次見面都像是不同的人
I want to know you more.
讓我想進一步認識你
I'm really sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Would you like to eat together tomorrow?
明天要不要一起吃飯？
I'll cook.
我來煮
No, I wouldn't.
不，不用了
Do you like rice or noodles?
你喜歡飯還是麵？
I like both, but…
兩邊都喜歡，但是…
Rice, I guess.
我會選飯
Do you like curry?
你喜歡咖哩嗎？
Curry? Yes, I do.
咖哩？我很喜歡
Do you like fried rice?
喜歡炒飯嗎？
I like fried rice.
我喜歡炒飯
Do you like omurice?
喜歡蛋包飯嗎？
-I like omurice too. -How about me?
-也喜歡蛋包飯 -那我呢？
I like…
也喜歡…
"Me"?
“我”？
Do you like me?
你喜歡我嗎？
Excuse me.
我先走了
I'm happy I got to see you.
能見到你，我很開心
You know, I can hear people's thoughts.
我可以聽到人們內心的想法
People's thoughts?
內心的想法？
That's scary.
好恐怖啊
I…
我…
like you.
喜歡你
THIS IS A SECRET, BUT IF YOU LIKE PIBIMBAP…
（這是祕密喔，韓式‘扳’飯的話 有一間名叫暖坑食堂的店更好吃）
GET ENERGIZED!
（能量補給！）
Good morning.
早安
-Good morning. -Morning.
-早安 -早啊
Good morning. Hello.
早安，嗨
Are you free? I want you to meet our new intern.
現在有空嗎？ 我想介紹今天新來的實習生
Oh, sure.
啊，好的
Come in.
進來吧
Huh?
什麼？
Yuri?
侑里小姐？
I knew we'd meet again.
我們果然又見面了
Subtitle translation by: Chul Woong Kim
字幕翻譯：沈庭葦
I've never done this before!
-我是第一次這樣！ -一起吃飯吧
-Cheers!
-乾杯！
We don't need workers who mix up their work and private life.
我們公司不需要公私不分的人
I love you.
我愛你
Why does he have to work under me?
為什麼他偏偏是我的下屬？
Are you drunk?
你醉了嗎？